eightcap.com 2016-12-27

# PRIVACY POLICY

  PRIVACY POLICY
  11.16
EIGHTCAP PTY LTD (ABN 73 139 495 944 - AFSL 391441), PRIVACY POLICY, 1 NOVEMBER 2016 PAGE | 0

INTRODUCTION                                                                        Collecting Sensitive Information –
                                                                                    Sensitive information is personal information about a person’s racial or ethnic
Protecting Your Privacy –                                                           origin, political opinion, membership of a political association, religious beliefs
Protecting your privacy and the confidentiality of your personal information is     or affiliations, philosophical beliefs, membership of a professional or trade
fundamental to the way EightCap Pty Ltd (EightCap) does business. EightCap          association, membership of a trade union, sexual orientation or practices,
values the ongoing trust you have in it to protect your privacy.                    criminal record, genetic information or health information.
This Privacy Policy explains how EightCap manages and protects your personal        EightCap will not collect, use or disclose sensitive information about you unless
information, including information that EightCap collects during the course of      it needs the information for one of its functions or activities and EightCap has
providing a product or service to you and the information EightCap holds after      your consent (or EightCap is legally required to do so).
your product or service is terminated (where it is required to hold this
information or it is necessary for its functions). This Privacy Policy also applies If you provide EightCap with personal information that it has not requested,
to information that EightCap collects from third-parties including the              then EightCap will endeavour to only retain the information that it is otherwise
information EightCap receives through the credit reporting system.                  entitled to hold because of the products and services it provides. However, if
                                                                                    this additional information is surplus to EightCap’s requirements but is provided
This Privacy Policy contains information about how you can access the               to EightCap in a manner where it is combined with information that EightCap
information EightCap holds about you, how you can ask EightCap to correct           is either required or entitled to retain then you acknowledge that this
your information and how you can make a complaint if you have concerns              unsolicited information may be held by EightCap in the same manner as the
about how EightCap has managed your information.                                    balance of your personal information.
How to Contact EightCap –                                                           Collecting Information Required by Law –
If you have any questions or would like more information about this Privacy         EightCap may collect information from you because it is required or authorised
Policy, you may contact EightCap directly on +61 3 8373 4800 at any time or         by an Australian law or court or tribunal order to collect that information.
email your question or request to customerservice@eightcap.com.                     EightCap will inform you if collection is required or authorised by law and
                                                                                    provide you with details of the law, court or tribunal order.
Privacy Framework –
EightCap is bound by the Privacy Act and the 13 Australian Privacy Principles       For example, when you set up a trading account and make a fund deposit,
(APPs) set out in that Act. The APPs regulate the way that certain entities         EightCap is required under the Anti-Money Laundering and Counter-Terrorism
handle personal information.                                                        Financing Act to collect certain information from you to prove your identity,
                                                                                    such as your driver’s licence or passport details. EightCap may collect
COLLECTING YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION                                                information to verify your identity even in the limited circumstances where the
EightCap collects your personal information so that it can perform its various      collection is not yet required by law.
functions and activities effectively. EightCap also collects your personal          EightCap may also collect your Australian tax file number (TFN). EightCap will
information if the law requires EightCap to collect it.                             only collect your TFN to determine whether you are subject to withholding tax
If EightCap does not collect your personal information, it may not be able to       on any payments you receive and for no other purpose. If EightCap collects
deal with you, or provide you with a product or service. Due to the nature of       your TFN, it will handle your TFN in accordance with the Privacy Act and the
the products and services EightCap provides and its associated regulatory           TFN Rule issued by the Commissioner.
obligations, EightCap does not have the option of allowing you to deal with it      Likewise, EightCap may be required to ask about your tax residency status
on an anonymous basis.                                                              under taxation information sharing agreements the Australian Government has
EightCap obtains most of the information directly from you, through                 in place with other countries. For example, a tax treaty between Australian and
application or other forms, and from maintaining records of information             the United States formed under US law (Foreign Account Tax Compliance Act)
provided in the course of ongoing customer service. For example, you provide        requires EightCap to ask account holders whether they are US citizens or US
EightCap with your information when you open an account, fill in an application     tax residents when they open an account. If you are a tax resident of another
form, deal with EightCap over the phone, send EightCap a letter, or use its         country, the relevant treaty or law may require EightCap to collect your
website(s).                                                                         relevant foreign tax identification number.
If you apply for one of EightCap’s products or services, EightCap may collect       USING YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION
and hold information from you including (but is not limited to) your name,
                                                                                    EightCap may use and disclose personal information it collects about you for
address, telephone number, email address, tax file number (TFN), date of birth,
                                                                                    several purposes including:
annual income and other financial details, employment details, credit history
                                                                                    » to consider your request for a product or service;
and your transaction history.
                                                                                    » to enable EightCap to provide a product or service;
Collecting Information from Third-Parties –                                         » to tell you about other products and services that may be of interest to
EightCap may also collect information about you that is publicly available,              you;
including information from telephone directories, the electoral role or other       » to assist in arrangements with other organisations in relation to a
websites.                                                                                promotion or provision of a product or service;
                                                                                    » to manage accounts or perform other administrative and operational tasks
There may be occasions when EightCap collects personal information about
                                                                                         (including risk management, systems development and testing, credit
you from a third-party. For example, EightCap may collect personal information
                                                                                         scoring and staff training, collecting debts and market or customer
from:
                                                                                         satisfaction research);
» credit reporting bodies – if EightCap requests a report about your credit
                                                                                    » to consider any concerns or complaints you raise against EightCap and/or
     history;
                                                                                         to manage any legal action between you and EightCap;
» other credit providers – if EightCap requests information from them about
                                                                                    » to prevent or investigate any actual or suspended fraud, unlawful activity
     the products they provide to you;
                                                                                         or misconduct;
» organisations that EightCap has an arrangement with to jointly offer products
                                                                                    » to identify you or establish your tax status under any Australian or foreign
     and/or has an alliance with to share information for marketing purposes – to
                                                                                         legislation, regulation or treaty pursuant to an agreement with any tax
     provide you with products or services and/or to promote a product or
                                                                                         authority; and
     service;
                                                                                    » as required by relevant laws, regulations, codes of practice and external
» related entities;
                                                                                         payment systems.
» marketing companies – if EightCap acquires contact information to tell
     people about EightCap’s products and services that may interest them; and      DISCLOSING YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION
» brokers and other parties who may have introduced you to EightCap.
                                                                                    Depending on the product or service concerned and particular restrictions on
EightCap may also collect information about how you use EightCap’s and other        sensitive information, when it is necessary, EightCap may need to disclose
websites to help EightCap better tailor its services to you. For example,           personal information about you to the following organisations:
EightCap may do this when you click on a link from EightCap’s website or visit      » related entities of EightCap in Australia, China and elsewhere in the world
a website which displays an EightCap’s advertisement. Usually, the information           which provide financial and other services for EightCap;
EightCap collects in this way is general information only derived from cookies      » service providers and specialist advisers who have been contracted to
– such as the number of visitors to a site or statistics about how a site is             provide EightCap with administrative, financial, taxation, insurance,
browsed – and does not identify you. If EightCap does identify you with this             research or other services;
information (for example, if you have been logged onto its online portal or
                                                                                    » credit reporting or reference agencies;
service), any use of disclosure of that information will be in accordance with
this Privacy Policy.
EIGHTCAP PTY LTD (ABN 73 139 495 944 - AFSL 391441), PRIVACY POLICY, 1 NOVEMBER 2016                                                                          PAGE | 1

»    if you were introduced to EightCap by a third-party, EightCap may disclose   MANAGING YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION
     personal and account information about you to them, their related
     companies and licensee or authorised representatives;                        Protecting Your Information –
»    credit providers, courts, tribunals and regulatory authorities as agreed or  EightCap takes all reasonable precautions to protect your personal information
     authorised by law;                                                           from misuse and loss, and from unauthorised access, modification and
»    anyone authorised by an individual, as specified by that individual or the   disclosure by ensuring that your personal information can only be accessed by
     contract.                                                                    people properly authorised to have access.
Note the above is not a complete list of the organisations to which your          EightCap trains its staff who handle personal information to respect the
information may be disclosed when using EightCap’s services. In some              confidentiality of customer information and the privacy of individuals. EightCap
circumstances, the nature of the product or service you request may require       regards breaches of your privacy very seriously and will impose appropriate
EightCap to disclose your information overseas and the countries to which it      penalties, including dismissal.
may disclose your information will depend on the particular circumstances.        EightCap may store your personal information in a combination of secure
When EightCap discloses your information (including cross-border disclosures),    computer storage facilities and paper-based files and other records, and
EightCap is required to take measures to ensure your information is treated in    irrespective of the format of the information, takes steps to protect the
accordance with the standards that apply in Australia except in rare cases (for   personal information it holds from interference, misuse, loss, unauthorised
example, where EightCap is required by law to disclose your information           access, modification or disclosure. EightCap maintains physical security, such
overseas) or unless where EightCap obtains your consent not to take these         as locks and security systems, over its paper and electronic data stores and
measures. Please keep in mind that EightCap’s ability to enforce the APPs or      premises. EightCap also maintains computer and network security. For
any other contractual privacy obligation against overseas recipients and to take  example, EightCap uses firewalls (security measures for the internet) and other
action in relation to any breach may be very limited and/or far less effective    security measures such as identification codes and passwords to control access
than it would be if such recipients were Australian based.                        to computer systems. EightCap continually maintains and monitors its online
                                                                                  security systems to ensure that EightCap’s online services are secure and that
Because the APPs may not apply or be enforceable against some overseas            your personal information is appropriately protected when you use these
recipients, EightCap understands that you may choose not to disclose your         services.
personal information. However, if you choose not to provide the information
EightCap needs to fulfil your request for a specific product or service, EightCap EightCap may need to maintain your personal records for a significant period
may not be able to provide you with the requested product or service.             of time. However, when EightCap considers the information is no longer
                                                                                  needed, it will remove any details that will identify you or it will securely
YOUR CONSENT IS IMPORTANT                                                         destroy the records.
EightCap requires your consent to use and/or disclose your information in         Protecting Your Privacy –
particular ways. For example, EightCap needs your consent if it needs to use      You can help EightCap to protect your privacy by staying informed about its
your information for a purpose that is not related to the purpose for which       security requirements and contacting EightCap immediately if your contact
EightCap collected your information in the first place.                           details change.
Depending on the circumstances, the consent may be express (for example, you      EightCap also requires you to keep your customer information such as
expressly agree to the specific use of your information by ticking a box) or      passwords and user details confidential and secure at all times. This means that
implied by some action you take or do not take (for example, your agreement is    you should not disclose your personal user information to any other person.
implied by the fact that you have agreed to your product terms and conditions     You should contact EightCap immediately if you believe that your personal user
which contains information about the use or disclosure).                          information may have been disclosed to another person or if you would like to
                                                                                  change your password or user details.
MARKETING & PRIVACY
                                                                                  ACCESSING YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION
As part of its service to you, EightCap may use personal information it has
collected about you to let you know about products and services or promotions     Under the Privacy Act (subject to certain exceptions), you have the right to find
and other opportunities in which you may be interested.                           out what personal information EightCap holds about you, including what
                                                                                  information it has obtained through the credit reporting system. You should
EightCap may contact you from time to time to let you know about new or           contact EightCap if you wish to find out about the personal information it holds
existing products or services. EightCap may also disclose your personal           about you – please note this request should be made in writing for security
information to related entities or business partners to enable them to tell you   reasons – EightCap will also need to verify your identity before giving you
about a product or service. You may contact EightCap at any time if you do not    access.
wish to receive such communications.
                                                                                  EightCap will normally be able to deal with your request immediately. However,
Note EightCap will not use any information it has received through the credit     if the request is complex, then such request will be dealt with within 14 to 30
reporting system for marketing purposes.                                          days. Further, depending on the complexity of your request, EightCap may
                                                                                  charge a fee to cover the cost of verifying the application and locating,
Website(s) and Cookies –
                                                                                  retrieving, reviewing and copying any material requested. If the information
EightCap’s website(s) may have links to external third-party websites that may
                                                                                  sought is extensive, EightCap will advise and disclose the likely cost in advance
benefit you. Please note that these third-party websites are not covered by this
                                                                                  and can help to refine your request if required.
Privacy Policy and these sites are not subject to EightCap’s privacy standards
and procedures.                                                                   Note in certain circumstances, EightCap may not be able to tell you what
                                                                                  personal information is held about you. In these circumstances, EightCap will
Likewise, EightCap uses cookies to give you access to certain pages of its
                                                                                  write to you to explain why it cannot provide you with the information and
website(s) without having to log in each time you visit. EightCap may also use
                                                                                  attempt to find alternative means to enable you to access your information.
independent external service providers to track the traffic and usage on its
website(s).                                                                       CORRECTING/UPDATING PERSONAL INFORMATION
Cookies are small pieces of text stored on your computer to help EightCap
                                                                                  If you believe that the personal information EightCap holds about you is
determine the type of browser and settings you are using, where you have been
                                                                                  inaccurate, incomplete or out-of-date as a result of changes of address and
on the website(s), what you’ve downloaded, where you came from, and to
                                                                                  other personal circumstances, you should contact EightCap as soon as possible.
ensure your information is secure. The purpose of this information is to provide
                                                                                  EightCap will promptly update any personal information that is inaccurate,
you with a more relevant and effective experience on EightCap’s website(s),
                                                                                  incomplete or out-of-date.
including presenting web pages according to your needs or preferences.
                                                                                  EightCap can generally update your personal information over the telephone,
Cookies are frequently used on many websites on the internet and you can
                                                                                  by email from your registered email address or online via the electronic trading
choose if and how a cookie will be accepted by changing your preferences and
                                                                                  service. Note EightCap will need to confirm your identity before making any
options in your browser. You may not be able to access some parts of
                                                                                  amendments.
eightcap.com if you choose to disable the cookie acceptance in your browser,
particularly the secure parts of the website. EightCap therefore recommends       RESOLVING YOUR PRIVACY CONCERNS
you to enable cookie acceptance to benefit from all the services on the website.
                                                                                  If you consider or believe that any action of EightCap breaches this Privacy
Note EightCap is constantly improving the functionality on its website(s). This   Policy or the Privacy Act or an applicable code or otherwise doesn’t respect
may mean a change to the way in which personal information is collected or        your privacy, you are entitled to make a complaint. This will be acted upon
used. The impact of any technology changes which may affect your privacy,         promptly.
will be notified in this Privacy Policy as it may be updated from time to time.
EIGHTCAP PTY LTD (ABN 73 139 495 944 - AFSL 391441), PRIVACY POLICY, 1 NOVEMBER 2016                                                                        PAGE | 2

You may lodge your complaint online at www.eightcap.com or by contacting
the Client Services Desk.
Telephone: +61 3 8373 4800 (9am – 7pm AEST weekdays)
Email: customerservice@eightcap.com
Alternatively, if your complaint is not satisfactorily resolved, you may also
contact the Complaint Resolution Manager who will work closely with you to
address your concern quickly and amicably.
Mail:
Attn: EightCap Complaint Resolution Manager
Level 11, 356 Collins Street, Melbourne, VIC 3000, AU
Managing Your Complaint –
If you make a complaint, EightCap will endeavour to respond within 48 hours
to let you know who is responsible for managing your complaint and will try to
resolve your complaint within 10 working days. When this is not possible,
EightCap will contact you within that time to let you know how long it will take
to resolve your complaint.
EightCap will investigate your complaint and where necessary, consult with
other credit providers or credit reporting bodies about your complaint.
EightCap will make a decision about your complaint and write to you to explain
its decision.
If you are not satisfied with the response given by EightCap to resolve your
complaint, you may wish to access an external dispute resolution service or
apply to the Office of the Australian Information Commissioner (OAIC) to have the
complaint heard and determined. When EightCap writes to you about its
decision, EightCap will also explain how you may access an external dispute
resolution scheme or make a complaint to the OAIC.
EIGHTCAP PTY LTD (ABN 73 139 495 944 - AFSL 391441), PRIVACY POLICY, 1 NOVEMBER 2016 PAGE | 3

                                                                                                                                                        PAGE | 4
EightCap Pty Ltd (EightCap) ABN 73 139 495 944. Australian Financial Services Licence Number 391441. © 2016 All Rights Reserved.
                                                                                                                                   www.eightcap.com
                                                                                                                                                      EIGHTCAP PTY LTD (ABN 73 139 495 944 - AFSL 391441), PRIVACY POLICY, 1 NOVEMBER 2016
